[
  {
    "question": "1. What is hashing?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2,
    "options": [
      "a) Sorting data in ascending order",
      "b) Rearranging data randomly",
      "c) Mapping data to a fixed-size array based on a key",
      "d) Searching for data in a linked list"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "2. What is a hash function?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1,
    "options": [
      "a) A function that generates random numbers",
      "b) A function that maps data of arbitrary size to fixed-size values",
      "c) A function that sorts data in descending order",
      "d) A function that counts the number of elements in a data structure"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "3. What is collision resolution in hashing?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
    "options": [
      "a) Handling the case when two keys hash to the same index",
      "b) Mapping keys to unique indices",
      "c) Rehashing the entire hash table",
      "d) Deleting keys from the hash table"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. What is a hash table?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) A table of hashed values",
      "b) A table with randomly arranged data",
      "c) A table of sorted data",
      "d) A data structure that implements hashing for efficient data retrieval"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "5. Which of the following is a common application of hashing?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2,
    "options": [
      "a) Sorting arrays",
      "b) Searching in a binary tree",
      "c) Implementing data structures like dictionaries and sets",
      "d) Rearranging linked lists"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "6. What is the purpose of a hash code?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
    "options": [
      "a) To represent the hashed value of a key",
      "b) To generate random values",
      "c) To sort data in ascending order",
      "d) To encrypt data for secure transmission"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "7. Which collision resolution technique involves chaining?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1,
    "options": [
      "a) Linear probing",
      "b) Separate chaining",
      "c) Quadratic probing",
      "d) Double hashing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "8. What is the load factor of a hash table?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) The number of elements in the hash table",
      "b) The size of the hash table",
      "c) The number of collisions",
      "d) The ratio of filled slots to the total number of slots"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "9. Which collision resolution technique rehashes when a collision occurs?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) Linear probing",
      "b) Separate chaining",
      "c) Quadratic probing",
      "d) Double hashing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "10. What is the worst-case time complexity of searching in a hash table?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1,
    "options": [
      "a) O(1)",
      "b) O(n)",
      "c) O(log n)",
      "d) O(n^2)"
    ]
  }
]